paytmbank.com 2018-03-26

# Paytm Payments Bank

Introduction and Objectives

This policy provides the details about the manner in which your data is collected, used and disclosed by the Bank. The Bank reserves the right to communicate your personal information to any third party that makes a legally-compliant request for its disclosure. Additionally, the Bank will share your personal information in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy.

The Bank values your trust & respects your privacy. The Bank will not use your email address/mobile number for unsolicited emails and/or SMS. Any emails and/or SMS sent by the Bank will only be in connection with the provision of agreed services & products and this Privacy Policy. Periodically, the Bank may reveal general statistical information about itself & its users, such as number of customers, number and type of services purchased, etc.

Information we collect

Information you provide (Personal Information)

Personal Information means and includes all information that can be linked to a specific individual or to identify any individual, such as name, address, mailing address, telephone number, email ID and any details that may have been voluntarily provided by you in connection with availing any of the services provided by the Bank

Information we get from your use of our services (Non-Personal Information)

Device-specific information

  * We may collect information on the browser you are using, the type of operating system you have, mobile network information and the device identifier details
  * This device information helps us to provide you with an online experience that matches your device and to manage our online advertising

Internet protocol address

  * We may collect the IP address of the device you use to connect to Internet

Location Information

  * When you use our services, we may collect and process information about your actual location using technologies for location determination such as IP address, GPS etc.

Cookies

  * A "cookie" is a small piece of information stored by a web server on a web browser so it can be later read back from that browser
  * The Bank may use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered
  * No personal information will be collected via cookies and other tracking technology; however, if you previously provided personally identifiable information, cookies may be tied to such information
  * Aggregate cookie and tracking information may be shared with third parties

How we use information we collect

Provide, maintain, improve and develop new

The Bank will use the personal/non-personal information collected from you to provide you with services & products that you have explicitly requested for, to resolve disputes, troubleshoot concerns, collect money, measure consumer interest in our services and develop new services that are better suited to your needs

Protect you and ourselves

The Bank will also use the information collected from you to help promote safe services, detect & protect you against error, fraud and other criminal activity, enforce the Bank’s terms and conditions, etc.

Offer you tailored /more relevant content

  * The Bank may also use your contact information to inform you about offers, products, services and updates based on your previous transactions and interests
  * The Bank may occasionally ask you to complete optional online surveys
  * These surveys may ask for your contact information and demographic information (like zip code, age etc.)
  * The Bank will use this data to customize your experience at the Bank’s digital platforms, providing you with content that might be of interest to you and to display content as per your preferences

Information we share

For legal reasons

**To ensure adherence to your right of protection from all kinds of communications, electronic or otherwise, which infringe upon your privacy, the Bank will:**

• Treat your personal information as private and confidential (even when you are no longer banking with us), and, as a general rule, not disclose such information to any other individual/institutions including its subsidiaries/associates, tie-up institutions etc. for any purpose unless:

    • You have authorized such disclosure explicitly, digitally or otherwise

    • Disclosure is compelled by law/regulation

    • Bank has a duty to the public to disclose i.e. in public interest

    • Bank has to protect its interests through disclosure

    • It is for a regulatorily mandated business purpose

• Ensure such likely mandated disclosures are communicated immediately to you in writing

With your consent 

The Bank will not use/share your personal information for marketing purpose, unless you have specifically authorized it

For external processing 

• On your consent/authorization, we may provide your personal information to our affiliates or other trusted businesses or persons or service providers engaged by us or financial institutions that we partner with to assist us with providing you with our services or to process it for us or partner financial institutions whose products/services shall be offered to you to better serve your needs and interests, based on our instructions and in compliance with our Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

• We may share your personal information with companies which we plan to merge with or are acquired by, which will follow the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy with respect to use of your personal data.

• You shall not disclose to any other person, in any manner whatsoever, any information relating to the Bank or its Affiliates of a confidential nature obtained in the course of availing the services through the Bank’s desktop website/mobile WAP site/mobile applications. Failure to comply with this obligation shall be deemed a serious breach of the terms herein and shall entitle the Bank or its Affiliates to terminate the services, without prejudice to any damages, to which you may be entitled otherwise

Disclaimer

Links to Other Sites

Our site links to other websites that may collect personally identifiable information about you. The Bank is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those linked websites

Consent 

• By using the Bank’s digital platforms and/or by providing your information, it is assumed that you have provided your consent to the collection and use of the information you disclose on these platforms in accordance with this Privacy Policy, including but not limited to your consent for sharing this information as per this Privacy Policy

• We recommend that you do not use/access Paytm Payments Bank website, WAP site or mobile applications, if you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy

Security

• The Bank has stringent security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under its control

• Whenever a customer changes or accesses his/her account information, the Bank offers the use of a secure server

• Once your information is in the possession of the Bank, it adheres to strict security guidelines, protecting it against unauthorized access

Policy Review & Updates

• This policy may change at any time without prior notification and will be reviewed as and when required

• To make sure that you are aware of any changes, we recommend that you review this policy periodically 

• This Privacy Policy shall apply uniformly to Paytm Payments Bank’s desktop website, mobile WAP site & mobile applications

Regulatory References

• Master Circular on Customer Service in Banks dated July 1, 2015

• RBI Charter of Customer Rights

• IBA Model Customer Rights Policy

• BCSBI Code of Bank's Commitment to Customers
